《异形》
(宇宙货船 诺斯托罗莫号)
(船员: 七名)
(货物: 二千万吨矿石)
(航道: 回航地球)
The food is terrible. Worst shit I've ever seen, man.
这里的伙食简直是给猪吃的
What you say? You got any biscuits over there?
你说呢?有饼干吗?
I keep seeing corn bread.
有玉米面包
- I am cold.   - Still with us, Brett?
- 好冷呀!  - 你没事吧,布瑞?
- Right.   - Oh, I feel dead.
- 没事  - 觉得好像死了一样
Anybody ever tell you you look dead, man?
没人说你看起来像死人吗?
Oh, yeah, right.
对了
Now, I just forgot something, man.
我忘了一件事
Before we dock,
回去之前
I think we oughta discuss the bonus situation.
我们该谈谈分红的事
Right. Brett and I, we think we oughta-
我觉得...
- We deserve full shares, right, baby?   - You see, Mr. Parker and I...
- 我们应该得到全部  - 我和派克...
feel that the bonus situation has never been on an equitable level.
都觉得很不公平
Well, you'll get what you're contracted for like everybody else.
你和别人一样都是按合约拿钱
Yes, but everybody else gets more than us.
大家拿的比我们多
Dallas, Mother wants to talk to you.
电脑老妈找你说话
Huh? Yeah, I saw it. Yellow light's for my eyes only.
好啦,亮黄灯就是叫我
Okay, get dressed, huh?
派克,穿衣服吧
Parker, come on. Can I finish my coffee? Thank you.
先让我喝完咖啡,谢谢
It's the only thing good on this ship.
船上只有咖啡好喝
Morning, Mother.
早上好,老妈
(界面2037请输入查询)
(怎么回事,老妈)
- Right.   - Okay.
- 可以吗?  - 好了
Plug us in.
启动吧
Thank you.
谢谢
- Where's Earth?   - You should know.
- 地球呢?  - 你应该知道
It's not our system.
这不是太阳系
Scan.
扫描
I can't believe this.
我不敢相信
Contact Traffic Control.
联络航管中心
This is commercial towing vehicle Nostromo out of the Solomons.
这里是诺斯托罗莫号货船
Registration number: 1-8-0-niner-2-4-6-0-niner.
编号180924609
Calling Antarctica Traffic Control. Can you read me? Over.
呼叫南极航管中心,听到吗?完毕
Commercial towing vehicle Nostromo out of the Solomons,
这里是诺斯托罗莫号货船
registration number-
编号
- Nothing.   - Keep trying.
- 没反应  - 继续试
Calling Antarctica Traffic Control. Do you read me, Antarctica? Over.
呼叫南极航管中心,听到吗?中心
I found it. Just short of Zeta II Reticuli.
找到了,靠近特奇拉星球
- We haven't reached the outer rim yet.   - That's hard to believe.
- 我们还没接近外围  - 好像不太妙
What the hell are we doing out here?
我们来这儿干嘛?
I don't know. What the hell are you talking about?
等等,你在说什么?
- That's not our system.   - I know that.
- 这不是太阳系  - 我知道
Do you ever notice how they never come down here?
知道他们为何都不下来?
I mean, this is where the work is, right?
他们以为工作不多?
Well, it's the same damn reason we get a half share to their one.
所以我们才分一半红
Our time is their time. That's the way they see it.
我们花的时间不值钱
No, but-Listen, man. Same old shit, man.
不,但是,听着,真老套
I think I know why they don't come down here.
你知道他们为何不下来?
It's because of you. You don't have no personality.
因为你很讨人厌
- Wonder what they want now.   - What's going on down here?
- 想知道他们现在需要什么  - 下面发生什么事?
- Um, you happen to be in my seat. Can I have it?   - Yes, of course.
- 这是我的座位  - 没错
- Thank you.   - I'm sorry.
- 谢谢  - 抱歉
What's happenin' now, baby?
怎么了?
Well, some of you may have figured out we're not home yet.
你们也发现我们还没到家
- We're only halfway there.   - What?
- 我们才在半途  - 什么?
Mother's interrupted the course of our journey.
电脑老妈改变了行程
Why? Yeah.
为什么?
She's programmed to do that should certain conditions arise. They have.
在某些状况下电脑可以做些改变
- Like what?   - It seems she has...
- 比如什么情况?  - 似乎...
intercepted a transmission of unknown origin.
电脑收到来历不明的信号
- She got us up to check it out.   - A transmission? Out here?
- 航道改变好让我们去查看  - 信号?在这儿?
- Yeah.   - What kind of a transmission?
- 没错  - 什么样的信号?
Acoustical beacon. It repeats at intervals of 12 seconds.
每隔十二秒一次的重复信号
- S.O.S.?   - I don't know.
- 求救信号?  - 不知道
Human?
人类吗?
- Unknown.   - Well, so what?
- 不明  - 又怎样?
We are obligated under section eight-
我们要遵守规定...
I hate to bring this up, but, uh,
别怪我多嘴
this is a commercial ship, not a rescue ship.
不过这是货船不是救生船
Right. And it's not in my contract to do this kind of duty.
没错,合约上没要我干这种事
And what about the money? If you wanna give me some money, I'll be happy to oblige.
有钱拿吗?如果有好处,我还可以考虑
The man's right. Let's go over the bonus situation.
他说得对,咱们谈谈分红的事吧
- I'm sorry. Can I say something?   - Let's talk about the bonus more.
- 我能插个嘴吗?  - 再谈谈分红的事吧
There is a clause in the contract which specifically states...
合约规定,收到有系统的通讯...
any systematized transmission indicating a possible intelligent origin...
可能来自有智慧生物...
- must be investigated.   - I don't wanna hear it.
- 我们就得去调查  - 我不想听
- We don't know if it's intelligent.   - I wanna go home and party.
- 我不知道是否智慧  - 我只想赶快回家
Parker, will you just listen to the man?
派克,听他说吧
On penalty of total forfeiture of shares. No money.
违约的话,酬劳全都泡汤,不付钱
You got that?
明白吗?
- Well, yeah.   - All right, we're going in.
- 明白  - 那就去吧
Yeah. We're goin' in, aren't we?
好吧,那就去吧
Can we all hear that, Lambert?
放出来让大家听,兰波特
Good God.
天啊
Doesn't sound like any radio signal I've heard.
不像一般无线电讯号
- Maybe it's a voice.   - Well, we'll soon know.
- 像在讲话  - 马上就知道
Can you hone in on that?
向对方发讯吧
What was the, uh, position?
告诉我方位
6550-99.
6550-99
All right. It found the quadrant.
好,找到象限了
Ascension: six minutes, 20 seconds.
上升度: 6分20秒
Declination: 39 degrees, two seconds.
倾度: 39度零2秒
Okay. Put that on the screen for me.
播放在荧幕上
All right. Well, that's it.
好,就这样
It's a planetoid. 1200 kilometers.
是个小行星,直径1200公里
- It's tiny.   - Any rotation?
- 好小  - 转速呢?
About two hours.
两小时自转一次
What about gravity?
地心引力呢?
Point eight-six.
0.86重力加速度
You can walk on it.
可以在上面走
Approaching orbital apogee.
快到轨道了
Mark 12, 11...
倒计时,12、11...
Equatorial orbit nailed.
进降落轨道
Nine, eight seconds on descent.
9、8秒后降落
- Grids energized. Fields focused.   - Five. Four...
- 网格划分完毕,已确认地点  - 5、4...
- D.O.R.'s on line.   - How's the status on the lifters?
- 垂直降落线定好  - 推进器的状况如何?
Give me an A.C. pressure reading.
给我压力指数
Forty-eight seconds and counting.
四十八秒,继续计时
SR-1stable.
SR-1稳定
Prepare to disengage from platform.
准备脱离平台
Mark, 20 seconds. Eighteen, 17-
还剩20秒...18、17秒...
Twelve, 11, 10,
12、11、10秒
nine, eight, seven,
9、8、7秒
six, five, four,
6、5、4秒
three, two, one, lock.
3、2、1秒,锁定
Disengage.
脱离
Umbilicus clear.
一切正常
Money's safe. Let's take her down.
安全了,下降吧
Nine, eight, seven-
9、8、7秒
Roll 92 degrees port yaw.
向左倾斜92度
Prime to port.
向左
Prime ventral. Prime dorsal.
向前,向后
Down a degree.
下降一度
39,000 meters.
39,000米
Turbulence.
乱流
Locked and floating. You can drop us anytime now. We'll catch you.
锁住,漂浮中,随时准备降落
Inertial damping's going off. Hold on, people. There's gonna be a little bump.
一开始会有点晃动,大家坐稳
What the hell was that?
那是怎么回事?
Pressure drop in intake three. Must've lost a shield.
压力下降,大概防护板掉了
Let's go with it.
继续进行
Dropping off now.
下降了
Still dropping.
持续下降
Here we are. We've got it.
好了
Take her down.
降落吧
Navigation lights on.
打开导航灯
We've got 5-3 still out. No problem. Just down 11%.
我们离地面还有3个5米,没问题,刚下降了11%
Grid status okay.
网格状态...OK
Fifteen,Still falling
15米,还在下降
Twelve,eleven,ten
12、11、10米...
Nine,
9米
eight, seven, six,
8、7、6米
five, four, three,
5、4、3米
two, one.
2、1米
Kill drive engines.
关掉引擎
What the hell happened?
怎么回事?
Somebody give me a straight answer!
快回答呀!
- Is the hull breached?   - I don't see anything. We've still got pressure.
- 船体破了吗?  - 看不到,压力还是很大
- Hit the screen.   - Right.
- 打开荧幕  - 马上
Secondary load sharing unit...
辅助支援系统...
is out.
故障
Three to four cells are gone.
四根架子坏掉三根
- Is that it?   - No, hold on.
- 就这样?  - 不,等一下
We can't fix it out here anyway, and we need to reroute...
没办法在这儿修好,线路得...
- a couple of these ducts, wouldn't you say, Brett?   - Dry dock time.
- 重新接好,你是内行,布瑞特  - 修复管线
Dry dock. Tell her we need to dry-dock.
叫他修复管线
Look, we couldn't fix it out here anyway.
没办法在这儿修好
We gotta reroute all these ducts,
线路得全部重整
and in order to do that we've got to dry-dock.
我们必须先修复主要管线
What else?
还有呢?
Some fragments kicked up,
出现一些碎片
and we've got to clean it all out and repressurize it.
我们必须清除和减压
How long before we're functional?
需要多少时间?
- Look, what is-What   - It's 17 hours, tell her.
- 这样...  - 就说要17小时
At least 25 hours. Yeah.
最少需要25小时
Get started on the floor panel. I'll be right down.
好吧,我马上下去
What the hell's she comin' down here for?
她下来干嘛?
She better stay the fuck out of my way, I'll tell you that.
她最好别惹我
I'd like to see what she's gonna do when she gets here.
我倒要看看她有什么本事
- Any response yet?   - No. Absolutely nothing.
- 有反应吗?  - 完全没有
Except the same transmission every 12 seconds.
还是每12秒重复一次
All the other channels are dead.
其他频道都故障了
Kick on the floods.
打开灯
We can't go anywhere in this. Mmm.
这么暗哪儿都不能去
Well, Mother says the sun's coming up in 20 minutes.
电脑说二十分钟后日出
- How far are we from the source of transmission?   - Uh, northeast.
- 我们离信号来源有多远?  - 东北
Just under 2,000 meters.
约二千米处
Walking distance?
走路能到吗?
Well...
呃...
- Can you give me an atmospheric?   - Yes.
- 分析大气组成  - 好的
It's almost primordial.
很原始的气体
There's inert nitrogen,
氮气
high concentration of carbon dioxide crystals, methane.
高浓度的二氧化碳,乙烷
I'm working on the trace elements.
再查其它的
- Anything else?   - Yes.
- 还有什么吗?  - 是的
It's...
还有...
rock, lava base,
岩石,主要成分熔岩
and deep cold.
很冷
Well below the line. Mm-hmm.
零度以下
I'll volunteer to be in the first group to go out.
我自愿打头阵
Yeah, that figures.
我就知道
You too, Lambert.
你也去,兰波特
- Swell.   - Better break out the weapons.
- 好吧  - 分发武器
I can't see a goddamn thing.
我什么都看不到
Ash, are you receiving?
收得到吗?
Good contact on my board.
这里接收良好
Clear and free. Keep the line open. Let's go.
把频道开着,走吧
Hey, Ripley.
蕾普莉
Hey, Ripley, I wanna ask you a question.
蕾普莉,我可以问个问题吗?
If they find what they're lookin' for out there, does that mean we get full shares?
要是他们找到东西能拿到全部红利吗?
Don't worry, Parker. You'll get whatever's coming to you.
别担心,不会少了你的
Look, I'm not gonna do any more work...
没讲清楚 ...
- till we get this straightened out.   - Brett,
- 我就不干活  - 布瑞特
- you're guaranteed by law to get a share.   - What?
- 法律保证你能分到钱  - 什么?
- Why don't you just fuck off.   - What?
- 你别烦我  - 什么?
What'd you say, Rip?
你说什么?
If you have any trouble, I'll be on the bridge.
有问题的话我在指挥舱
Hey, Ripley, come back here!
蕾普莉,回来呀!
- Son of a bitch.   - What's the matter?
- 王八蛋  - 怎么了?
Can't see a goddamn thing.
什么也看不见
- Quit griping.   - I like griping.
- 别抱怨了  - 我就喜欢抱怨
Come on. Knock it off.
别吵了
Ash, can you see this?
你看得到吗?
Yes, I can.
看得到
I've never seen anything like it.
我从没看过这种东西
Very bizarre.
很怪异
You said it.
你说过几遍了
All right.
好了
Moving on to second... position.
朝第二目的地前进
What is it?
那是什么?
Let's get out of here.
咱们离开吧
We've got this far. We must go on.
既然来了,一定要继续
We have to go on.
一定要继续
- Will you say that again?   -  Shit.
- 请再说一次  - 可恶
Ash, as you can see, it's kind of hard to describe.
很难形容这玩意
I'm going back to the console.
我回去主机查询
Seems to be solid.
快下来
To walk-You can on it.
这儿有怪东西
Dallas?
达拉斯
Come on down here. Something different down here.
快下来,下面有异状
I don't know what it is, but-
不知道是什么
See if we can get up that wall. If we can get up that wall, we can find out.
翻过那道墙就看得到
Amazing.
神奇
Alien life-form.
异形
Looks like it's been dead a long time.
死了很久
Fossilized.
变成化石了
Looks like it's grown out of the chair.
好像长在椅子上一样
Bones are bent outward,
骨头往外弯
like he exploded from inside.
大概是从体内爆出来的
Wonder what happened to the rest of the crew.
其他船员呢?
Let's get the hell out of here.
我们出去吧!
Hey, Dallas, Lambert, come on over here.
嘿,达拉斯,兰伯特,快来看看
Come on.
快点
- What do you got?   - See what you make of this.
- 找到什么?  - 你看这是什么?
Ash.
艾希
That transmission-Mother's deciphered part of it.
那个讯号..."老妈"已经破译了一部分
- It doesn't look like an S.O.S.   - What is it, then?
- 不像是求救讯号  - 那么是什么?
Well, I-It looks like a warning.
看来像警告
- I'm gonna go out after them.   - What's the point?
- 我要去找他们  - 有什么用呢?
I mean, by the time it takes to get there, you'll...
等你赶到
they'll know if it's a warning or not, yes?
他们早就知道是不是警告了
You okay down there?
下面还好吧?
- Can you see anything?   - Uh... a cave.
- 看到什么?  - 这是个洞穴
A ca-A cave of some sort. But l-
一个洞穴
Well, I don't know, but it's like the goddamn tropics in here.
这他妈像热带一样热
What the hell is this?
这是什么玩意?
The cave is completely enclosed,
洞内完全密闭
and it's full of...
全是...
leathery objects, like eggs or something.
皮状的东西,好像是颗蛋
There's a layer of mist...
蛋表面有一层薄膜...
just covering the eggs that reacts when broken.
一碰就有反应
Kane? You all right?
肯恩,你没事吧?
I'm okay. All right.
没事
I'm okay. I just slipped.
没事,只是滑了一下
Appears to be completely sealed.
完全被封住
Wait a minute. There's movement.
等一下,有动静
It seems to have life. Organic life.
好像是活的生物
- You there, Ripley?   - I'm right here.
- 你还在吗?蕾普莉?  - 我在这儿
- Okay, Ripley, I'm at the inner lock hatch now.   - Right.
- 我在内舱门  - 好
- Ripley. We're clean. Let us in.   - Right here.
- 干净了,让我们进去  - 马上
- What happened to Kane?   - Something has attached itself to him.
- 肯恩呢?  - 有东西吸附住他
- We have to get him to the infirmary right away.   - What kind of thing?
- 我们要马上把他送医务室  - 什么东西?
- I need a clear definition.   - An organism. Open the hatch.
- 说清楚点  - 一种生物,快开门
Wait a minute. If we let it in, the ship could be infected.
等一下,他可能会污染整艘船
You know the quarantine procedure-24 hours for decontamination.
按照隔离规定来做,要隔离24小时
He could die in 24 hours. Open the hatch.
等那么久他早没命了,快开门
Listen to me. If we break quarantine, we could all die.
要是感染,大家都会死
Look, would you open the goddamn hatch? We have to get him inside.
快开门,我们得把他送进去
No. I can't do that.
不行
And if you were in my position, you'd do the same.
要是你也会这么做
Ripley, this is an order. Open that hatch right now.
蕾普莉,我命令你开门
- Do you hear me?   - Yes.
- 听到吗?  - 听到
Ripley, this is an order! Do you hear me?
蕾普莉,我命令你,听到吗?
Yes, I read you. The answer is negative.
听到,不过我不接受
Inner hatch opened.
内舱门开了
My God.
天啊
What the hell is that?
那是什么东西?
Jesus Christ.
天啊
What is that, man?
那是什么?
Hey, how the hell is he breathing?
他是怎么样呼吸?
Is he still alive or what?
他到底是不是还活着?
Why don't you guys freeze him?
你们为什么不把他冷冻?
How come they don't freeze him?
他们怎么不把他冷冻?
What's going on in there?
到底怎么回事?
- What the fuck is going on?   - You bitch!
- 到底在搞什么鬼?  - 你这贱人!
Jesus Christ! Hey! Hey!
老天
- You would've left us out there.   - Break it up.
- 你想把我们留在那里  - 拦住她
Ripley, when I give an order, I expect to be obeyed.
蕾普莉,我下达命令是要别人遵守
- Even if it's against the law?   - You're goddamn right!
- 违法的也是吗?  - 一点也没错!
Maybe she has a point. Who the hell knows what that thing is.
她说得有理,天晓得那是什么
How are we gonna get that off him?
怎么弄掉这个东西?
- How are we gonna get it off?   - I'm gonna get some instruments.
- 怎么弄掉它?  - 好啦,我去拿东西
My God.
天啊
Right. I'll make an incision here.
好,我先把这个割掉
Try and remove one of the digitals from-You're gonna do what?
然后再把这玩意弄下来,你要干什么?
Finger. I'm gonna try and get his finger off. Just a minute.
触手,把它的触手割断,先夹起来
- No, that's not-It's tearing his scalp.   - I know!
- 不行,头皮会被扯下来  - 我知道!
It's not coming off without tearing his face off with it.
不把脸皮割下来,这东西不会善罢甘休
We'll have to take a look at him inside. Right.
我得看看里头
How come they don't freeze him?
干嘛不把他冷冻起来?
How come you guys don't freeze him?
怎么不把他冷冻起来?
All right, you can take your mask off.
可以除下口罩了
- What's it got down his throat?   - I would suggest it's feeding him oxygen.
- 他的喉咙里有什么东西?  - 它大概在输氧给他
Paralyzes him, puts him in a coma, then keeps him alive.
让他麻痹、昏睡,让他活命
Now what the hell is that?
到底是什么?
- We gotta get it off of him.   - Just a minute.
- 一定要弄下来  - 等一下
Just a minute.
等一下
I mean, let's not be too hasty.
先别急
We don't know anything about...
我们对那玩意...
it.
一无所知
Now, we're assuming it's feeding him oxygen. If we remove it,
假设它在输氧给他,割除的话
it could kill him.
他恐怕就会死
I'm willing to take that chance. Let's cut it off him now.
我愿意冒这个险,现在就割除
- You'll take responsibility?   - Yes, I'll take responsibility. Get him out of there.
- 你要负责?  - 我要负责,把他抬出来
Where do you wanna do this?
你要从何着手?
We'll make an incision just below the knuckle there.
从关节的地方切开
Right here. Stand by.
这里?
Good God!
我的天啊!
That crap's gonna eat through the hull.
船体被侵蚀
That thing's gonna eat through the goddamn hull. Come on!
船体会被蚀穿,快走吧!
What's going on?
发生什么事?
This way.
这里来
Next deck.
下一层
There it is.
在那儿
Don't get under it! Don't get under it.
别站在下面,别站在下面
Looks like it's stopping.
好像停止了
Take a look at this, man. Yeah.
你看看
Brett, give me-What do you got, a pen there? Give it to me, quick.
给我笔,快给我
Come on! Come on!
快给我,快给我
Don't get any on your arm.
别弄到手上
It stopped.
干了
Don't see anything like that except, uh, molecular acid.
没看过这玩意,一定是硫酸
It must be using it for blood.
一定是它的血
It's got a wonderful defense mechanism.
好强的防卫能力
You don't dare kill it.
绝不能杀死它
What about Kane?
肯恩怎么办?
- Here's your pen back.   - What do we do now?
- 还给你  - 现在怎么办?
Leave Kane to Ash. You get back to work.
找艾希处理,你回去工作
Well, what-
什么
Okay.
好了
Try it.
试试看
Damn it. I thought sure that was it.
我肯定是那里
Try it again.
再试一次
I feel like I've been in this place a month.
我好像待在这鬼地方好久了
We shouldn't have landed in this place in the first place.
我们根本不该来这儿
Shouldn't have landed on this damn ball, I know that.
早就不该来这臭星球
Well, the sooner we patch this thing up and get out of here, the sooner we can go home.
赶快修好就回去吧,早点回家
This place gives me the creeps.
这地方好恐怖
That's amazing. What is it?
好可怕,什么东西?
Ah, yes, it is. Um-
是很可怕
I don't know yet.
还不知是什么
Did you want something?
有事吗?
Yes. I, uh-
是的,我...
I'd like to have a little talk. How's, uh-How's Kane?
我想聊聊,肯恩情况如何?
He's holding. No changes.
没什么变化
And, uh, our guest?
那么...咱们的客人呢?
Well, as I said, I'm still...
我说过,我还在...
collating, actually, but, uh,
研究,但是
I have confirmed that he's got an outer layer of protein polysaccharides.
我确定表皮有蛋白质多糖类物质
He has a funny habit of shedding his cells...
它会脱除死细胞...
and replacing them with... polarized silicon,
长出新的矽石
which gives him a prolonged resistance...
所以对周围环境...
to adverse environmental conditions.
适应性很强
- Is that enough for you?   - That's plenty.
- 满意吗?  - 满意
- What does it mean?   - Please don't do that. Thank you.
- 什么意思呢?  - 别这样,谢谢
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Well, it's an interesting combination of elements,
这玩意有这些成分
making him a tough little son of a bitch.
所以很顽强
And you let him in.
是你放它进来的
I was obeying a direct order, remember?
我只是服从命令,记得吗?
Ash, when Dallas and Kane are off the ship,
当达拉斯和肯恩不在船上时
I'm senior officer.
我就是指挥官
Oh, yes. I forgot.
没错,我忘了
You also forgot the science division's basic quarantine law.
你也忘了卫生署的检疫规定
- No, that I didn't forget.   - Oh, I see.
- 不,我没忘  - 我明白
You just broke it. Huh?
你却违规了?
Look, what would you have done with Kane? Hmm?
换作是你,你会怎么做?
You knew his only chance of survival was to get him in here.
你知道这是他唯一的生存机会
Unfortunately, by breaking quarantine,
你违规
you risk everybody's life.
却危及大家的性命
Maybe I should've left him outside.
我应该把他留在外面
Maybe I've jeopardized the rest of us, but it was a risk I was willing to take.
也许我害了大家,不过我得冒这个险
That's a pretty big risk...
这是很大的风险...
for a science officer.
你这科学研究员
It's, uh, not exactly out of the manual, is it?
这不必看书就知道的
I do take my responsibilities as seriously as you, you know.
我跟你一样很重视职责
You do your job...
你尽你的职责...
and let me do mine, yes?
也让我尽我的职责
- Where's Dallas?   - In the shuttle.
- 达拉斯呢?  - 他在舱房
- Dallas.   - I think you should have a look at Kane.
- 达拉斯  - 你该去看看肯恩
- Why?   - Something's happened.
- 为什么?  - 情况有变化
- Serious?   - lnteresting.
- 很严重吗?  - 很有趣
Ripley, meet me in the infirmary right away.
蕾普莉,请到医疗室
Where is it?
那东西呢?
Well, I don't know. I mean, we ought to try and find it.
不知道,最好去找
Yeah, let's check it.
快去找
Dallas, please be careful.
达拉斯,小心点
Sorry.
对不起
No, not in the corner. Psst. Have one of these.
不在里面,你也拿一支
Just in case.
以防万一
Kane? Dallas?
肯恩?达拉斯?
- You okay?   - I didn't see it. Was it in the overhead?
- 你还好吗?  - 我没看见,在上头吗?
- What? It was up there somewhere. - My God.
- 什么?好像在上头  - 我的天
- Cover up the damn thing!   - Wait.
- 快盖起来!  - 等等
That's alive!
还活着!
That's a reflex action.
没事,是条件反射
Well, we've gotta have a look at this.
看看这个
Excuse me.
抱歉
- Seems dead enough.   - Well, good. Let's get rid of it.
- 看起来死了  - 那就快把它丢掉
Ripley, for God's sake,
蕾普莉,老天
this is the first time that we've encountered a species like this.
我们第一次见到这生物
It has to go back. All sorts of tests have to be made.
应该带回地球化验
Ash, are you kidding? This thing bled acid.
别开玩笑,它的血都是强酸
Who knows what it's gonna do when it's dead.
谁知道它死了会怎样?
Think it's safe to assume it isn't a zombie.
至少它不是僵尸
Dallas, it has to go back.
达拉斯,把它带回去
Well, I'd soon...
我猜...
as not burn it at the stake, but you're the science officer.
应该不会错,你是科学研究员
- It's your decision, Ash.   - Dallas.
- 你决定吧  - 达拉斯
How come I've got to change my mind? The decision's been made.
已经下决定,没办法改变
I'm not trying to change your mind, Dallas. I just want you to listen-
你不必改变,我只要你听我说
Will you listen to-
听我说
Just tell me how you can leave that kind of decision to him.
为何让他决定?
Look, I just run the ship.
我只负责开船
Anything that has to do with the science division, Ash has the final word.
有关科学方面的事全让艾希决定
- How does that happen?   - It happens, my dear, because that's what the company wants to happen.
- 怎么会这样?  - 因为这是本公司的规定
Since when is that standard procedure?
这并不是标准程序
Standard procedure is to do what the hell they tell you to do.
标准程序是乖乖听话
- What's happening with the repairs? How's it going?   - They're pretty much finished now.
- 修理得如何?  - 差不多好了
Why the hell didn't you tell me so?
你怎么不早说?
- Because there's still some things left to do.   - Like what?
- 因为还有很多工作  - 什么工作?
Well, we're blind on "B" and "C" decks.
B、C层停电
- The reserve power system's blown   - That's a bunch of horseshit.
- 备用电源也坏了  - 胡说八道
- We can take off without that.   - Yeah, we can. You think that's a good idea?
- 就算这样也能起飞  - 是可以,你觉得那是个好主意?
Look, I just wanna get the hell out of here, all right?
我只想早点离开这,好吗?
Dust in the intakes again. Number two's overheating.
管道有灰尘,二号引擎过热
Spit on it for two minutes, would you, for Christ's sake?
再撑二分钟就行了,拜托
We're hot. We're getting hotter.
愈来愈热
Engine room, red clip status?
引擎室情况如何?
- One kilometer on ascension.   - Engage artificial gravity.
- 上升一公里  - 启动人工引力
- Engaged.   - I'm altering the vector now.
- 启动  - 我要改变方位,开始
Inhibit C.N.G. control.
收回降落架
- Struts retract.   - Struts retracted.
- 收回  - 收回了
Max stress to fifth overload.
5倍承载压力
Ease it back.
轻而易举
She's great. Beautiful.
飞船性能真好
Walk in the park. When we fix something, we stay fixed.
是我们修好的
- Don't we, Brett baby?   - Right.
- 对吧?  - 对
What I think we should do is just freeze him.
把他冷冻起来吧
If he's got a disease, why don't we stop it where it is?
谁知道他染上什么病
- He can always get to a doctor when we get back home.   - Right.
- 回到地球再找医生  - 没错
Whenever he says anything, you say "right," Brett. You know that?
无论他说什么你都说没错
Right.
没错
Parker, what do you think? Your staffjust follows you around, says "right."
你的好兄弟,老是说你没错
- Just like a regular parrot.   - Yeah. Shape up.
- 像只八哥一样  - 是呀
- What are you, some kind of parrot?   - Right.
- 拜托,别像只八哥  - 没错
Come on. Knock it off! Kane's gonna have to go into quarantine.
够了,肯恩得接受检疫隔离
That's it. Yes, and so will we.
我们也一样
Well, how about a little something to lower your spirits?
我有坏消息
Thrill me, will you, please?
什么事?
Well, according to my calculations,
我计算
based on time spent getting to and from the planet-
我们多花的时间...
- Just give me the short version. How far to Earth?   - Ten months.
- 长话短说,还要几天到地球?  - 十个月
- Oh, God.   - Great.
- 天哪  - 这下可好
Yes.
说吧
Dallas, I think you should come and see Kane.
达拉斯,你最好来看看肯恩
- Has his condition changed?   - It's simpler if you'd just come and see him.
- 他有变化吗?  - 你最好亲自来看看
We're on our way.
马上就来
Right.
没错
How are you doing?
你还好吗?
- How you doin'?   - Thank you.
- 你还好吗?  - 谢谢
Um, terrific. Next silly question.
好得很,下一个笨问题
Oh, thank you.
谢谢你
Do you remember anything about the planet?
你记得些什么吗?
What's the last thing you do remember?
你记得的最后一件事是什么?
I remember some...
我记得我梦到...
horrible dream about... smothering.
被什么东西闷死
And-
还有
And-Anyway, where are we?
我们在哪里?
- Right here.   - We're on our way home.
- 这里  - 回程中
Back to the old freezerinos.
又回到太空中
Could I have something to eat before we go back?
给我点吃的,我饿坏了
I-I need something myself.
我也饿死了
Yeah, right. One more meal before bedtime. I'm buyin'.
一起吃宵夜,我请客
Hey, that's a break. Bedtime.
好棒
The first thing that I'm gonna do when I get back...
我一回到地球...
is to get some decent food.
就要吃顿大餐
I can dig it, man. Let me tell you, I've eaten worse food than this,
对呀,吃什么都比这些好
but then I've tasted better, you know what I'm sayin'? The other one over there.
这里简直是猪食,知道吗
Well, you pound down the stuff like there's no tomorrow.
你们好像明天就没得吃了一样
I'd rather be eatin' something else, but, uh, right now I'm thinkin' food.
我宁愿来点别的...我现在只想到食物
Well, you should know. You know what it's made of.
俗语说食色性也
No, man, I don't wanna talk about what it's made of.
我可没想那么多
I'm eatin' this just to-
我只想吃这个
What's the matter?
怎么了?
The food ain't that bad, baby. What's wrong, Kane?
没这么难吃吧?肯恩,怎么了?
Are you choking?
噎着了?
What's wrong?
怎么了?
What? What?
怎么了?什么事?
- This is serious.   - Kane, what's the matter?
- 糟糕了  - 肯恩,怎么了?
It's okay!
没事的!
Hold him down! Hold him-
按住他
Get the spoon in!
拿汤匙
Damn it!
见鬼!
- Get it into his mouth!   - I'm trying!
- 放在他嘴里!  - 我正在试
Oh, my God! Oh, God!
天啊!
No! Don't touch it! Don't touch it!
别动它!别动它!
Dallas?
达拉斯?
- Dallas?   - Yeah.
- 达拉斯?  - 什么事
- Anything?   - No. You?
- 找到什么吗?  - 没有,你呢?
Nothing.
没有
- You see anything?   - No.
- 看到什么吗?  - 没有
Inner hatch sealed.
内舱封闭
Anybody wanna say anything?
有人想说什么吗?
This is just an ordinary prod, like a cattle prod.
这看起来像是普通的赶牛棍
It's got a portable battery.
里头有干电池
It's insulated all the way here, all the way up to here.
那儿到这儿都不通电
Just make damn sure nobody puts their hand on the end of it.
千万别碰到顶端
It shouldn't damage the little bastard,
除非那玩意皮很薄
unless its skin's thinner than ours.
否则伤不了它
But it will give him a little incentive.
不过会把它吓一跳
Now we just have to find it.
现在只要找到它
I've taken care of that. I've designed this tracking device.
交给我,我设计了一个追踪器
You just set it to search for a moving object, like so.
以移动的东西为目标
Hasn't got much of a range, but when you get within a certain distance,
范围不大,不过只要进入范围
it'll start to give off a signal.
就有讯号
What's it key on?
原理是什么?
Micro changes in air density.
空气密度产生微妙变化
Give me a demo.
我试试看
See? Again.
像这样
Got ya.
明白
Two teams. Ash, Lambert and l.
分两组,艾希、兰波特和我
Ripley, you take Parker and Brett.
蕾普莉,你和派克及布雷特
Now, anyone see this thing, you catch it in the net...
现在谁发现它,就用...
that Parker's holding on his lap.
派克拿的网子抓住
Parker, I don't want any heroics out of you, all right?
派克,别再扮英雄了
Catch it, put it in the air lock, get rid of it.
抓到后丢进空气舱射出去
Now, channels are open on all decks.
频道全都开放
I want you to communicate, keep in touch at all times, all right?
随时保持联络,好吗?
Let's go.
走吧
I thought you fixed 12 module.
我以为都修好了
We did.
是修好了
I don't understand it.
我也不懂
The circuits must have burned out.
电路大概烧坏了
- What do we got here?   - Damn it! Hold your light over here, would you?
- 怎么样?  - 拿灯照过来
Yeah, that's it.
对了
I don't know if this is gonna work.
不知道管不管用
If I could just put this-put this in there.
放进去那里
- Right.   - Oh, damn it.
- 好的  - 妈的
Check the insulation.
看看绝缘体
Oh, shit!
可恶
- Steady.   - According to this, it's within five meters.
- 别动  - 仪器显示,它在五公尺以内
Micro changes in air density, my ass.
空气密度变化个屁
It's within five meters.
在五公尺以内
Be careful.
小心点
- Christ.   - Don't do that. Don't creep up on me with that thing.
- 天啊  - 别挤过来
You guys, stick together.
我们要在一起
- Don't fail me now.   - What?
- 别让我失望  - 什么?
What is it? Parker, Brett, it's in this locker!
派克,在置物柜里
Where?
哪里?
Here, take this.
拿去
Get over there and get the net.
到那边,张开网
Get it? I got it. I got it. I got it.
让我来!让我来!让我来!
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
等等!等等!
All right, Parker. When I say.
我一说就打开
All right. Now.
打开
Easy.
小心
Wait! Don't let him go!
别让它跑掉!
What the hell are you doing, man?
你在干什么?
It's the cat.
那只是只猫
Hey, look, now. We had to bag it, man.
你得逮到它
Now we might pick it up on the tracker again.
看看追踪器有没有讯号
I'll-I'll-I'll-Go and get it, man.
快去呀,你最好快去
All right. You get him. We'll go on.
你去捉猫,我们去找
Here, kitty!
小猫咪!
Here, kitty, kitty!
来呀!小猫咪!
Enough of that kitty crap.
臭猫咪!
Jones.
乔西!
Jonesy?
小乔西!
Here, Jonesy.
来呀!乔西!
Jonesy?
小乔西?
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
来呀!小猫咪!
Here, Jonesy.
来呀!乔西!
Jonesy?
乔西?
Here, kitty, kitty.
来呀!小猫咪!
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
小猫咪!小猫咪!
Here, Jonesy.
过来!宝贝!
Jonesy.
好猫咪!
Kitty, kitty.
小猫咪!小猫咪!
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
小猫咪!小猫咪!小猫咪!
Jonesy?
乔西?
Hey. Hey. Come on, Jonesy.
过来!宝贝!
Come on, baby. That's a kitty.
好猫咪!
That's a kitty. Come on, baby.
这才是好猫咪,过来!宝贝!
That's a kitty.
这才是好猫咪
Hey, hey. I'm not gonna hurt you.
我不会伤害你
Come on.
过来!
Brett!
布雷特!
Whatever it was, it was-it was big and-
不管它是什么,那玩意真的很大
You're sure it took him into the air shaft?
你确定它把他拖进了通风口?
Disappeared into one of the cooling ducts.
在一条冷却管里消失了
No question, it's-it's using the air ducts to move around.
很显然它利用通风道出没
Could he want Brett alive?
布雷特还活着吗?
- What?   - Could Brett be alive?
- 什么  - 布雷特还活着吗?
No. I mean, I don't think so.
不,我不认为
Well, this air shaft may work to our advantage.
它在通风道对我们有利
Here it leads up to and comes out in the main air lock.
通风道通往主空气舱
All right. There's only one big opening along the way.
中间只有一个维修孔
We can cover that up, and then we...
堵住出口,然后...
drive it into the air lock and zap it into outer space.
把它赶进空气舱,再把它丢出太空
This son of a bitch is huge!
这玩意大得很!
- I mean, it's like a man. It's big!   - Kane's son.
- 跟人一样大  - 肯恩的儿子
Come on, Ash. Science department should be able to help us.
艾希,你是科学官
What can we do to drive it?
我们该怎么把它赶出去?
Yes, well, it's adapted remarkably well to our atmosphere,
它很能适应我们的大气状态
considering its nutritional requirements.
考虑到它对营养的需求
- The only thing we don't know about is temperature.   - Okay. What about temperature?
- 不知道的是它的温度  - 温度怎么样?
- What happens if we change it?   - Let's try it.
- 改变后会怎样?  - 咱们试试看
I mean, most animals retreat from fire. Yes?
动物都怕火
Fire, yeah. Parker, can you rig...
火,没错,你能打造...
three or four incinerator units?
三、四支喷火枪吗?
Give me about 20 minutes. I'll do it.
给我二十分钟时间就行
- Who gets to go into the vent?   - I do.
- 谁去进通气管?  - 我去吧
No. You and Ash...
不,你和艾希...
take the main air lock.
到主气舱室
Parker, Lambert, you cover up that maintenance opening, please.
派克和兰波特封住维修孔
Right.
好的
- I'm at the first junction.   - Dallas, I'm right here.
- 我在第一节  - 达拉斯,我在这儿
- Parker?   - Yeah?   - Lambert?
- 帕克?  - 在?  - 兰波特
We're in position. I'm just trying to get a reading here.
我们已就位,正在侦测
- The air lock is open.   - Okay, Ripley.
- 空气舱打开  - 好的,蕾普莉
Ready.
准备
All right. I've got a reading on you now.
我读到你的讯号
Uh, open the hatch to the third junction.
打开第三节的闸门
Okay, I'm through.
好了,我通过了
- Ripley?   - Yes.
- 蕾普莉?  - 收到!
Close all the hatches behind me.
关掉我身后所有的舱门
I'm moving on.
我要继续前进了
Dallas, hold it a minute. I think I got it.
达拉斯,等等,好像找到了
- Yes, I've got it.   - Where?
- 找到了  - 在哪儿?
It's somewhere around the third junction.
在第三节附近
Okay, moving on.
好,继续前进
It is right around there. Now, Dallas, you're gonna have to be careful.
就在这附近,小心点
All right. I've reached...
好了,我到了...
the third junction, and I'm going down.
第三节,我要下去了
The hell's the matter with that box?
那盒子怎么样了?
Dallas, you're gonna have to hold your position for a minute. I-
达拉斯,暂时别动
I've lost the signal.
讯号不见了
What? You sure?
什么?你确定?
Look around. Are you sure it's not there? It's got to be around there somewhere.
确定不在那儿吗?一定在附近
Checked it out, Lambert. You may be getting interserence.
再检查看看,可能有干扰
Dallas, are you sure there's no sign of it?
没有迹象吗?刚才还在
I mean, it is there. It's gotta be around there.
一定就在附近
- Dallas?   - God, what is happening?
- 达拉斯?  - 天啊,发生什么事了?
All right.
好吧
Uh, am I-am I clear, Lambert? I want to get the hell out of here.
安全吗?我想走了
Oh, God. It's moving right towards you.
天哪,它朝向你去
Move! Get out of there! Behind you! Move!
快走!快走呀!
Dallas! Move, Dallas! Move, Dallas!
达拉斯!快逃!达拉斯!快逃!
Get out! Move!
快逃!快逃!
The other way!
不,往另一边
Dallas?
达拉斯?
- Oh, no.   - Take it easy.
- 不  - 冷静点
Dallas?
达拉斯?
We found this laying there.
我找到这个
No blood.
找不到血迹
No Dallas. Nothing.
找不到达拉斯,什么都没有
- How come I don't hear nobody saying nothing?   - I'm thinking.
- 大家怎么不讲话?  - 我正在想
Unless somebody has got a better idea,
除非谁有更好的办法
we'll proceed with Dallas's plan.
否则就照计划进行
What? And end up like the others?
什么?像他们那样吗?
Ohh. No, you're out of your mind.
不,你疯了
- Got a better idea?   - Yes. I say that we abandon this ship.
- 你有更好的主意吗?  - 有,咱们应该弃船
We get the shuttle and just get the hell out of here.
搭太空梭逃走
We take our chances and just hope that...
赌赌运气,希望...
- somebody picks us up.   - Lambert.
- 有人会救我们  - 兰波特
- The shuttle won't take four.   - Then why don't we draw straws and-
- 太空梭载不了四个人  - 那就抽签吧
I'm not drawin' any straws. I'm for killing that goddamn thing right now.
我不抽签,我要把它杀掉
Okay.
好的
Well, let's talk about killing it.
那就商量怎么杀它
We know it's using the air shafts-Will you listen to me, Parker?
它走通风道...你在听吗,派克?
- Shut up!   - Let's hear it.
- 闭嘴!  - 说吧
Let's hear it.
好,说吧
It's using the air shafts.
它走通风道
- We don't know that.   - That's the only way.
- 我们不知道  - 那是唯一的路
We'll move in pairs. We'll go step by step...
两人一组,我们一步一步...
and cut off every bulkhead and every vent...
切断每一个通风孔...
until we have it cornered, and then we'll blow it the fuck out into space.
等我们困住它,再把它丢进太空炸碎
Is that acceptable to you?
可以吗?
- If it means killing it, it's acceptable to me.   - Obviously it means killing it.
- 只要能杀了它,我就干  - 当然,就是杀了它
But we have to stick together.
我们得团结一致
- How are our weapons?   - The weapons are fine.
- 喷火枪够不够?  - 没问题
- This one needs refueling.   - Will you get it, please?
- 这支需要燃料  - 去拿吧
- Ash, go with him.   - No, no. I can manage, Ash.
- 艾希,跟他去  - 不用
Don't follow me.
别跟来
Ash?
艾希
Any suggestions from you or Mother?
你和电脑老妈有什么建议吗?
No, we're still collating.
没有,我还在评估
You're what?
什么?
You're still collating?
还在评估?
I find that hard to believe.
我不敢相信
- What would you like me to do?   - Just what you've been doing, Ash.
- 我还能做什么?  - 就像这样
Nothing. I've got access to Mother now,
什么也不要做,我能进电脑室
and I'll get my own answers, thank you.
我自己去问
All right.
好吧
(请解释为何无法消灭异形)
(无法解释)
(请进一步说明)
(无法说明)
(937特别指令只准科学官查问)
(紧急质问编号100375,特别指令937是什么)
(诺斯托罗莫号变更航道)
(调查外星生物,采集标本)
(第一优先,安全带回标本以供分析)
(其它则为次要因素)
(可以放弃船员)
There is an explanation for this, you know.
我可以解释
Is there really? I don't wanna hear your goddamn explanation!
真的吗?不必解释了
I want-I want-
我想要...我想要...
I want-I w-
我想要...
Parker. Lambert?
派克,兰波特?
Ash, open the door.
艾希,把门打开
Ash-
艾希!
Will you open the door?
把门打开
Let me by, Ash.
让我过去
The hell are you doing?
你做什么?
Get her up. Get her up. Get her up. Get her up. Get her up. Get her up.
拉她起来!拉她起来!拉她起来!拉她起来!
Android! He's an android!
生化人,他是生化人!
Jesus!
老天!
It's a robot. Ash is a goddamn robot!
他是机器人,根本就是机器人!
God!
天啊!
Oh! Get off me-Oh!
帮我把这玩意弄开!
Holy shit!
见鬼!
Help! Help me get this fucking thing off!
帮我把这玩意弄开!
God! Jesus! Oh, God! Oh, God!
天啊...老天
How come the company sent us a goddamn robot?
公司怎么会派生化人来?
All I can think of is they must've wanted the alien for their weapons division.
可能是武器部想要异形吧
He's been protecting it right along.
他一直都在保护它
Parker, will you plug it in?
派克,插进去
- I don't know why   - Because he may know how to kill it.
- 为什么?  - 他知道怎么杀死异形
Ash, can you hear me?
艾希,你听得到吗?
Ash?
艾希?
Yes, I can hear you.
我听得到
- What was your special order?   - You read it. I thought it was clear.
- 你的特别指令是什么?  - 你也看过,指令很明白
- What was it?   - Bring back life-form.
- 什么?  - 把异形带回去
Priority one. All other priorities rescinded.
是第一优先,其他的都不重要
The damn company! What about our lives, you son of a bitch?
该死的公司,我们的命呢?王八蛋
I repeat: All other priorities are rescinded.
我重覆,其他的都不重要
How do we kill it, Ash?
怎么杀死它?
There's got to be a way of killing it. How-How do we do it?
一定有办法的,怎么杀死它?
You can't.
杀不死的
- That's bullshit! - You still don't understand what you're dealing with, do you?
- 放屁  - 你还不知道它是什么,对吧?
A persect organism.
完美的有机体
Its structural persection is matched only by its hostility.
构造和攻击能力都很强
You admire it.
你很崇拜它
I admire its purity.
我崇拜它的纯净
A survivor...
强者生存...
unclouded by conscience,
不被良知
remorse or delusions of morality.
悔意和道德左右思想
Look, I-I've heard enough of this,
我听够了
and I'm asking you to pull the plug.
切掉他的电源
- Last word.   - What?
- 最后一句,蕾普莉  - 什么?
I can't lie to you about your chances, but...
老实说,你们也没生存机会的...
you have my sympathies.
但我同情你们
We're gonna blow up the ship.
我们得把船炸掉
We'll take our chances in the shuttle.
咱们搭太空梭
- Blow up the ship.   - Good.
- 把船炸掉  - 好
Come on.
走吧
- When we throw the switches, how long before the ship blows?   - Ten minutes.
- 启动之后多久会爆炸?  - 十分钟
- No bullshit.   - If we ain't outta here in ten minutes,
- 别唬我  - 十分钟不走
we won't need no rocket to fly through space.
就别想搭太空梭了
We're gonna need coolant for the air support system.
冷冻系统需要冷却剂
You two go down, get all the coolant you can carry.
能拿多少就尽管拿
I'll get the shuttle ready. I'll give you about...
我去启动太空梭,我等你们
about seven minutes.
七分钟后回来
Come back up here. I'll shut the switches off,
你们一回来就打开开关
and we'll blow this fucker off into space.
把这臭东西炸到外太空
Okay. All right. Come on.
好的,行动
- Ready?   - Take care of yourself.
- 好了吗?  - 好了,小心点!
Seven minutes.
七分钟
Take it easy.
别紧张
Jones.
乔西?
Jones?
Okay, check the bottles.
检查瓶子
Jones?
乔西?
- How you doin'?   - Fine.
- 情形如何?  - 还好
Kitty.
小猫咪
Okay. Go ahead.
好!快点!
Jones?
乔西?
Psst! Psst! Psst! Psst! Kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
小猫咪!小猫咪!小猫咪!
Come here, Jones. Come here.
来吧!乔西!来吧!
Jones?
乔西?
Come here, boy.
来吧!小子!
Come here.
来吧!
Nice kitty.
好猫咪!
Jones?
乔西?
Come here. Come here, sweetheart.
过来!宝贝!
Jones.
乔西?
Jones? Jones?
乔西?乔西?
Jones?
乔西?
Jones! Goddamn it!
乔西!可恶!
Now I got you.
找到你了
Here, sweetie. Nice kitty.
来吧!宝贝!好猫猫!
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
- Get out of the way.   - I can't get out of the way!
- 让开!  - 不行!
Get out of the way, Lambert! It's gonna kill us!
让开!让我干掉它!
I can't!
不行!
- Lambert, for Christ's sake, get out of the way!   - Parker? Lambert-
- 兰波特!天啊!快滚开!  - 帕克?兰波特?
Get out of the way, Lambert!
快走开!兰波特!
Parker? Lambert?
帕克?兰波特?
Lambert? Parker?
兰波特?帕克?
Get outta the room!
快走吧!
Oh, God!
天啊!
Parker?
帕克?
(危险!紧急毁灭系统)
(开启后十分钟将爆炸)
Danger. The emergency destruct system...
危险!紧急毁灭系统...
is now activated.
已经启动
The ship will detonate in T-minus...
开启后十分钟...
ten minutes.
将爆炸
The option to override automatic detonation...
紧急毁灭系统已开启...
expires in T-minus five minutes.
太空船将在十分钟后爆炸
The option to override automatic detonation...
五分钟后将无法解除...
expires in T-minus-
自爆系统
Dallas.
达拉斯?
Brett.
布雷特
- Oh.   - Kill me.
- 噢  - 杀了我
Kill me!
杀了我!
The option to override automatic detonation...
三分钟后...
expires in T-minus...
将无法解除...
three minutes.
自爆系统
The option to override...
一分钟后...
automatic detonation expires...
将无法解除...
in T-minus one minute.
自爆系统
Twenty-nine, 28, 27,
29、28、27秒
26, 25, 24,
26、25、24秒
23, 22,
23、22秒
21, 20 seconds.
21、20秒
Nineteen, 18,
19、18秒
17, 16,
17、16秒
15, 14, 13,
15、14、13秒
12, 11, 10 seconds.
12、11、10秒
Nine, eight, seven,
9、8、7秒
six, five, four,
6、5、4秒
Come on! three, two, one.
3、2、1秒
The option to override detonation procedure...
现在无法解除...
has now expired.
自爆系统
Mother? I've turned the cooling unit back on.
电脑老妈,我打开冷却系统
Mother!
电脑老妈!
The ship will automatically destruct...
本船将于五分钟后...
in T-minus five minutes.
自动爆炸
You bitch!
臭电脑!
Goddamn it!
可恶!
Jonesy.
乔西
You now have one minute to abandon ship.
一分钟内必须撤离本船
The ship will automatically destruct...
一分钟后...
in T-minus one minute.
自动爆炸
(脱离)
T-minus 30 seconds.
倒数计时三十秒
Twenty-nine, 28,
29、28秒
27, 26,
27、26秒
25, 24,
25、24秒
23, 22, 21,
23、22、21秒
20 seconds.
20秒
Nineteen, 18,
19、18秒
17, 16,
17、16秒
15, 14, 13,
15、14、13秒
12, 11, 10 seconds.
12、11、10 秒
Nine, eight, seven,
9、8、7秒
six, five,
6、5秒
four, three, two, one.
4、3、2、1秒
I got you,
宰了你
you son of a bitch.
混帐东西
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
嘘!嘘!嘘!嘘!
It's all right.
没事了
Shh, shh, shh.
嘘!嘘!嘘!
Shh, shh, shh. It's all right.
嘘!嘘!嘘!没事了!
All right. It's nice to see you too.
好了,很高兴再见到你
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
嘘!嘘!嘘!嘘!
It's okay.
没事了
Come on. Come on.
来吧!
You are.
你是
My lucky star.
我的幸运星
You... are my.
你是我的
Lucky star.
幸运星
You.
你
Lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky.
幸运星!幸运星!幸运星!
Okay.
好!
Well, come on.
来吧!
You are.
你是
My lucky star.
我的幸运星
You.
你
You are my lucky star.
你是我的幸运星
You are my lucky.
Oh, my God.
天啊!
My-My lucky-
我的
You... are my.
你是我的
You are my.
Lucky.
幸运星
Final report of the commercial starship Nostromo.
星际货船诺斯托罗莫号,最后报告
Third officer reporting.
三级军官最后报告
The other members of the crew-
其他的船员
Kane, Lambert,
肯恩、兰波特
Parker, Brett,
派克、布雷特
Ash and Captain Dallas-are dead.
艾希以及达拉斯船长全部丧命
Cargo and ship destroyed.
货物和货船全都毁灭
I should reach the frontier in about six weeks.
我在六周后将抵达边界
With a little luck, the network will pick me up.
幸运的话,有人会来搭救
This is Ripley, last survivor of the Nostromo,
我是蕾普莉,诺斯托罗莫号唯一生还者
signing off.
报告完毕
Come on, cat.
来吧!猫咪!